Edna O'Brien papers, circa 1939-2000
Emory University
- Correspondence, 1939-2000, Series 1; Boxes 1-18
  - Alphabetical correspondence, 1955-2000, Subseries 1.1; Boxes 1-12
    - Woman's View, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 68)
    - Women of the Year Luncheon, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 69)
    - Wood, Audrey, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 70)
    - Wood, Robin, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 71)
    - Woodfall Film Production, undated (Box 12, Folder 72)
    - Woolf, Cecil, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 73)
    - Woolley, Sue, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 74)
    - The Writers' Guild of Great Britain, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 75)
    - Wroe, Nick, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 76)
    - The Wylie Agency, 1996-1999 (Box 12, Folder 77)
    - Wylie, Andrew, 1991-1998 (Box 12, Folder 78)
    - Wyndham, Francis, 1968-1999 (Box 12, Folder 79)
    - W-unidentified (Box 12, Folder 80)
    - The Yale Review, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 81)
    - Yglesias, Rafael, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 82)
    - Young, Gertrude, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 83)
    - Y-unidentified (Box 12, Folder 84)
    - Zamecka, Wanda, 1965-1968 (Box 12, Folder 85)
    - Zeichner, Judy, undated (Box 12, Folder 86)
    - Z-unidentified (Box 12, Folder 87)
  - Family correspondence, 1939-1999, Subseries 1.2; Boxes 13- 14
    - Bailey, Pat (O'Brien), 1959-1979 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Bailey, Pat (O'Brien), 1982-1999 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Bailey, Pat (O'Brien), undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Bailey-Howe, Sally Ann, 1978-1997 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Blake, Eileen (O'Brien), 1960-1987 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Blake, Marian, 1969-1975 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Gebler, Adolfe and Marianne, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Gebler, Carlos (and family), 1968-1999 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Gebler, Carlos (and family), undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Gebler, Ernest, 1954-1989 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Gebler, Sasha, 1968-1997 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - O'Brien, Helena (Cleary), 1948-1975 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - O'Brien, Helena (Cleary), ca. 1970's (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - O'Brien, Helena (Cleary), undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - O'Brien, John, 1949-1977 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - O'Brien, Michael, 1939-1983 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Personal correspondence, 1960-1999, Subseries 1.3; Box 15
    Arranged in chronological order.
    - 1960-1989 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 1990-1999 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Fan correspondence, 1966-1997, Subseries 1.4; Boxes 16-17
    - "Letters from Maniacs, 1966" (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - 1968-1971 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - "Re: BBC, 'A Chance to Meet,' October 1971" (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - 1972-1978 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - 1981-1988 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - 1991-1997 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Restricted correspondence, 1973-1997, Subseries 1.5; Box 18
    - Fortune, John, November 1973- December 1974 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Fortune, John, 1974-June 1975 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Hamilton, Iain, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Heaney, Marie, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Owen, David (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Personal Letters of Peter Reed and Goran Palin (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Trinity College Library, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Journals, 1951-1999, Series 2; Boxes 19-26
  The journals series, currently restricted, includes over fifty items, written between ca. 1951 and 1999. Some of the early journals include annotations by Ernest Gebler. Other, later journals include detailed records of O'Brien's dreams, attempts at self-analysis, confessions, and observations.
  Special restrictions apply: Entire series closed to researchers.
  - ca. 1951 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - 1951-1952 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - 1953 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - 1957-1961 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - ca. 1963 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - 1963-1964 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - 1966-1968 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - ca. 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - 1970, March 25-April 12 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - 1970, October 29 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - 1974, September 3 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - 1975, November and 1977, November (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - 1976, January 17 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - 1977, February 19 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - 1978, May (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - 1979, January 26 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - 1979, August 10 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - ca. 1980 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - 1981, May 9 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - 1981, Summer (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - ca. 1981, "Immortal Longings" (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - 1982, January 6-September 24 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - 1983, January (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - 1983, January 24 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - 1984, January (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - 1984, June (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - 1986, August (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - ca. 1986 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - 1988, December-1989, September (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - 1990, January-1992, May (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - 1991, "Dreams" (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - 1994-1995, "Suicide" (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - 1994-1995, "Suicide" (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - 1994-1995, "Suicide" (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - ca. 1994-1995 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - ca. 1994-1995 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - 1995-1996, "Suicide" (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - 1997, September (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - undated, "Italy" (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - undated, "LSD and Other Joys" (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - undated, "#2 for Exile" (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Writings by O'Brien, ca. 1953-1999, Series 3; Boxes 27-78; OP1
  The writings by Edna O'Brien found in the collection include manuscripts of poems, novels, short stories, essays, plays, and screenplays written between ca. 1953 and 1999. Subseries 3.1 includes individual poems, both collected and uncollected. Many of the poems were written under the pen name Dina Bryan. Subseries 3.2 includes manuscripts and typescripts of O'Brien's prose. The short stories are arranged chronologically by collection and alphabetically within each collection; the uncollected short stories are arranged alphabetically. O'Brien's novels are arranged chronologically. The subseries also contains nonfiction pieces. O'Briens essays and short nonfiction pieces are arranged alphabetically and the book-length nonfiction is arranged chronologically. At the end of this subseries are drafts of O'Briens writings for children. Of particular note in this subseries is an early typescript of Girls in Their Married Bliss with corrections and annotations by Ernest Gebler. Subseries 3.3 consists of manuscripts and typescripts of O'Brien's plays and screenplays. O'Brien's published plays and screenplays are arranged chronologically, the others are arranged alphabetically.
  Organized into three subseries: (3.1) Poems, (3.2) Prose, and (3.3) Scripts.
  - Poems, Subseries 3.1; Box 27
    - On the Bone (1989)
    - On the Bone, MS and TS (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Unpublished Collections
    - A Child Again, TS (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Uncollected Poems
    - "Adultery," TS (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - "Ambition," TS (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - "Autumn," TS (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - "Christmas," TS [see Subseries 3.1, Uncollected Poems, "Autumn"]
    - "Summer," TS [see Subseries 3.1, Uncollected Poems, "Autumn"]
    - "Back," TS (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - "Beginnings," TS (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - "Boy," TS (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - "But," TS (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - "Christmas Gift," TS (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - "Couple," TS (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - "Crazy," TS (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - "The Day Fluff was Sent for Messages," TS (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - "Elopement," MS (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - "The End," TS (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - "Father," TS (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - "Female," TS (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - "Foxglove," TS (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - "Getting Over It," TS (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - "Goodbye," TS (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - "Growths," TS (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - "Hope," TS (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - "I'm Blessed With My Servants," MS and TS (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - "Interim," TS (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - "It Doesn't Hurt," TS (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - "Lady MacBeth Herself," TS (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - "Last Love," TS (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - "A Lay Teacher's Prayer," TS (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - "Letter from the Mad," TS (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - "Love," TS (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - "Male," TS (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - "May Be," TS (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - "Memorandum," TS (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - "Metamorphosis," TS (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - "Mission," TS (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - "Moment," TS (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - "Mother," TS (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - "Newcomer," TS (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - "Paul and His Hobbies," TS (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - "Rat Words," TS (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - "Requiem," TS (Box 27, Folder 41)
    - "Resurrection," TS (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - "Sally's Surprises," TS (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - "Shame," TS [variant title: "Where"] (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - "Silver Jubilee," TS (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - "Soldier," TS (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - "A Son," TS (Box 27, Folder 47)
    - "Song," TS (Box 27, Folder 48)
    - "Songs for the Fun of It," TS (Box 27, Folder 49)
    - "Spring," TS (Box 27, Folder 50)
    - "Strabane," TS (Box 27, Folder 51)
    - "Telephone Conversation," TS (Box 27, Folder 52)
    - "To Those at the Front," TS (Box 27, Folder 53)
    - "Toil," TS (Box 27, Folder 54)
    - "Twin," MS (Box 27, Folder 55)
    - "Virgin Fancy," TS [variant title: "A Young Girl's Fantasy"] (Box 27, Folder 56)
    - "Wild Flowers," TS (Box 27, Folder 57)
    - "Wish," TS (Box 27, Folder 58)
    - "You," TS (Box 27, Folder 59)
    - Untitled, MS and TS (Box 27, Folder 60)
  - Prose, 1960-1999, Subseries 3.2; Boxes 28-59
    - Collected Short Stories
    - The Love Object (1968)
    - "The Love Object," TS (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - "Paradise," TS (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Mrs. Reinhardt and Other Stories (1978)
    - "Mrs. Reinhardt," TS (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - "Number Ten," TS (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Returning (1982)
    - "The Doll," TS (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - "Ghosts," TS (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - "My Mother's Mother," TS (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - A Fanatic Heart (1984)
    - A Fanatic Heart, Proof (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Lantern Slides (1990)
    - "Another Time," MS (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - "Brother," TS (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - "A Demon," TS (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - "Dramas," TS (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - "Epitaph," Notebook [variant title: "Violets"] (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - "Epitaph," MS, TS and Proof [variant title: "Violets"] (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - "Lantern Slides," TS (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - "Long Distance," TS (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - "What a Sky," TS (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Lantern Slides, Proof (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Lantern Slides, Proof (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Lantern Slides, Proof (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Uncollected Short Stories
    - "The Actor," TS (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - "Among Maples," TS (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - "Angel," TS (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - "Blood," TS and Proof (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - "Children," TS (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - "The Cottage," TS (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - "Cottage in the Mountains," TS (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - "Cycles," TS (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - "Dark Rosaleen," MS and TS (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - "A Decayed Bachelor," TS (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - "Diary of an Unfaithful Woman," TS (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - "Dusk," TS (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - "During Luncheon," TS (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - "Elfin Green Mushroom," TS (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - "Friday's Appointment," MS and TS (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - "Friends for Life," TS (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - "Good Friday," TS (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - "Green Georgette," TS (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - "Jansen," TS (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - "Like Marbles," TS (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - "Little Wild Duck," TS (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - "Love," TS (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - "Love's Lessons," MS and TS [variant titles: "Letters to a Loved One," "Nomads," and "Cold Cuts"] (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - "Love's Lessons," MS and TS [variant titles: "Letters to a Loved One," "Nomads," and "Cold Cuts"] (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - "Love's Lessons," MS and TS [variant titles: "Letters to a Loved One," "Nomads," and "Cold Cuts"] (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - "Love's Lessons," TS and Proof [variant titles: "Letters to a Loved One,” "Nomads," and "Cold Cuts"] (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - "Madonna," TS (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - "Meeting," TS (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - "Mother," TS (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - "Mummys Don't Cry," TS (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - "Mystic Love," TS (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - "A Myth," TS (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - "New in Manhattan," TS (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - "Parents," TS (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - "The Plan," TS (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - "The Pool," TS (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - "Rapid," TS (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - "The Return," TS (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - "A Schoolgirl's Tale," TS (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - "The Scream," MS (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - "The Spa," TS (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - "Suicide," TS (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - "The Telephone," TS (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - "A Town House," TS (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - "Topsy," MS (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - "The Trees," TS (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - "Walking," TS (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Untitled, MS and TS (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Novels
    - The Lonely Girls (1962)
    - The Lonely Girls, TS bound (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - The Lonely Girl, TS bound (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Girls in Their Married Bliss (1964)
    - Girls in Their Married Bliss, TS (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - A Pagan Place (1970)
    - A Pagan Place, Research material (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Night (1972)
    - Night, Proof with corrections (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Night, Galley proof with corrections (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Night, Master galley proofs, May 11, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Night, Master page proofs, May 12, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Johnny I Hardly Knew You (1977)
    - Johnny I Hardly Knew You, Notebook (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Johnny I Hardly Knew You, Notebooks (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Johnny I Hardly Knew You, MS (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Johnny I Hardly Knew You, MS and TS (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Johnny I Hardly Knew You, Proof (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - The Country Girls Trilogy and Epilogue (1986)
    - The Country Girls Trilogy and Epilogue, "Epilogue," TS (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - The High Road (1988)
    - The High Road, Notebooks (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - The High Road, Notebooks (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - The High Road, Notebooks (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - The High Road, Notebook (Box OP1)
    - The High Road, MS and TS (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - The High Road, TS [1 of 2] (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - The High Road, TS [2 of 2] (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - The High Road, TS (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - The High Road, TS [1 of 2] (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - The High Road, TS [2 of 2] (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - The High Road, Galley proof, 13 June, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Time and Tide (1992)
    - Time and Tide, Author's note, TS (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Time and Tide, Book jacket material, 1992 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Time and Tide, Notebook (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Time and Tide, Notebooks (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Time and Tide, Notebooks (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Time and Tide, Notebooks (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Time and Tide, Notebooks (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Time and Tide, Notebooks (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Time and Tide, Notebooks (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Time and Tide, Notebooks (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Time and Tide, MS and TS [1 of 2] (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Time and Tide, MS and TS [2 of 2] (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Time and Tide, MS and TS (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Time and Tide, MS and TS (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Time and Tide, MS and TS (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Time and Tide, MS and TS (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Time and Tide, MS and TS (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Time and Tide, MS and TS (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Time and Tide, MS and TS (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Time and Tide, MS and TS (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Time and Tide, MS and TS (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Time and Tide, MS and TS (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Time and Tide, MS and TS (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Time and Tide, MS and TS (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Time and Tide, MS and TS [1 of 2] (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Time and Tide, MS and TS [2 of 2] (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Time and Tide, MS and TS (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Time and Tide, TS [1 of 2] (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Time and Tide, TS [2 of 2] (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Time and Tide, TS (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Time and Tide, TS (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Time and Tide, TS (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Time and Tide, TS (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Time and Tide, TS (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Time and Tide, TS (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Time and Tide, TS (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Time and Tide, TS [Excluded section] (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Time and Tide, TS [1 of 2] (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Time and Tide, TS [2 of 2] (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Time and Tide, TS [1 of 3] (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Time and Tide, TS [Folder 2 of 3] (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Time and Tide, TS [3 of 3] (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Time and Tide, TS (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Time and Tide, TS (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Time and Tide, TS (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Time and Tide, TS (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Time and Tide, TS [1 of 5] (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Time and Tide, TS [2 of 5] (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Time and Tide, TS [3 of 5] (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Time and Tide, TS [4 of 5] (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Time and Tide, TS [5 of 5] (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Time and Tide, TS (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Time and Tide, TS (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Time and Tide, Proof with corrections [1 of 3] (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Time and Tide, Proof with corrections [2 of 3] (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Time and Tide, Proof with corrections [3 of 3] (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Time and Tide, Proof, 21 January, 1992 [1 of 2] (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Time and Tide, Proof, 21 January, 1992 [2 of 2] (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Time and Tide, Master proof, 22 January, 1992 [1 of 2] (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Time and Tide, Master proof, 22 January, 1992 [2 of 2] (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Time and Tide, Galley proof (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Time and Tide, Galley proof (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Time and Tide, Galley proof [1 of 2] (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Time and Tide, Galley proof [2 of 2] (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Time and Tide, Galley proof (bound) December 1991 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Time and Tide, Galley proof, 19 February, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Time and Tide, Master galley proof [1 of 2] (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Time and Tide, Master galley proof [2 of 2] (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Time and Tide, Notes, MS and TS (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Time and Tide, Notes, MS and TS (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Time and Tide, Notes, MS and TS (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - House of Splendid Isolation (1994)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, Notebooks (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, Notebooks (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, Notebooks (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, MS and TS (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, MS and TS (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, MS and TS (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, MS and TS (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, MS and TS (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, MS and TS (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, MS and TS (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, MS and TS (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, MS and TS (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, MS and TS (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, MS and TS (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, TS (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, TS [1 of 2] (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, TS [2 of 2] (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, TS (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, TS [1 of 2] (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, TS [2 of 2] (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, TS 10 January, 1993 [1 of 2] (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, TS 10 January, 1993 [2 of 2] (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, TS, 8 February, 1993 [1 of 2] (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, TS, 8 February, 1993 [2 of 2] (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, TS (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, TS (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, TS (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, TS [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, TS [2 of 2] (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, TS (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, Galley proof (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - The House of Splendid Isolation, Notes (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Down By the River (1996)
    - Down by the River, Book jacket material (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Down by the River, Notebook (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Down by the River, Notebooks (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Down by the River, Notebooks (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Down by the River, Notebooks (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Down by the River, Notebook (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Down by the River, Notebooks (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Down by the River, Notebooks (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Down by the River, Notebook (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Down by the River, MS (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Down by the River, MS and TS (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Down by the River, TS (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Down by the River, TS [1 of 3] (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Down by the River, TS [2 of 3] (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Down by the River, TS [3 of 3] (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Down by the River, TS [1 of 3] (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Down by the River, TS [2 of 3] (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Down by the River, TS [3 of 3] (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Down by the River, TS [1 of 3] (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Down by the River, TS [2 of 3] (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Down by the River, TS [3 of 3] (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Down by the River, Galley proof, 27 June, 1996 [1 of 2] (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Down by the River, Galley proof, 27 June, 1996 [2 of 2] (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Down by the River, Galley proof, 14 November, 1996 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Down by the River, Galley proof, 18 November, 1996 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Down by the River, Notes (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Down by the River, Research material (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Down by the River, Research material (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Down by the River, Research material (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Unpublished Novels
    - A Novel of Lena and Michael, TS (Box 56, Folder 6)